Printed Maps Printed.Maps
American Philosophical Society
- Oceans - World
  - Atlantic Ocean
    - Wreck chart of the North Atlantic coast of America. U.S. Navy Department. Hydrographic Office. Bureau of Navigation. Richardson Clover, Lt. Commander, U.S. Navy, Hydrographer. Washington: 1893., 1630; Size: 62.1 x 58 cm.; Size of paper: 87 x 61.5 cm.; Colored.; Richardson Clover.
      Gives list of wrecks and derelicts, etc., from 1887 to 1891.
    - Monthly pilot charts of the North Atlantic and Mediterranean. London: E. Weller & Grahams Ltd. Litho.: 1901-1902., 1631; 16 maps.; Size: 46 x 65.7 cm.; Colored.; E. Weller & Grahams Ltd
      Charts for January, April-December 1901, and January-May 1902.
    - Physiographic diagram Atlantic Ocean (Sheet 1) by Bruce C. Heezen and Marie Tharp. Geological Society of America, Special Paper 65. Reprinted by permission of the Lamont Geological Observatory (Columbia University). [Washington]: 1957., 1632; Scale: Vertical exaggeration about 20:1.; Size: 71.7 x 141.2 cm.; Colored.; Bruce C. Heezen and Marie Tharp.
      See: Geological Society of America, Special paper, no. 65. New York: Geological Society of America: 1957.
    - Physiographic diagram of the South Atlantic Ocean, the Caribbean Sea, the Scotia Sea and the eastern margin of the South Pacific Ocean. By Bruce C. Heezen and Marie Tharp. Lamont Geological Observatory, Columbia University. Published by the Geological Society of America. Washington: Williams & Heintz Map Corp.: 1961., 1633; Size: 142.2 x 118.7 cm.; Colored.; Bruce C. Heezen and Marie Tharp.
  - Indian Ocean
    - Indischer Ocean. Commodore B. V. Wüllerstorf-Urbair, S. M. Fregatte Novara. 1857. [Vienna]: K.-K. Hof- u. Staats-Druckerei: [ca. 1860]., 1634; 7 maps.; Scales: Various.; Size of paper: Ca. 80 x 56.5 cm.; B. V. Wüllerstorf-Urbair.
    - Physiographic diagram of the Indian Ocean the Red Sea, the South China Sea, the Sulu Sea and the Celebes Sea by Bruce C. Heezen and Marie Tharp. Lamont Geological Observatory, Department of Geology, Columbia University. Published by the Geological Society of America. Washington: Williams & Heintz Map Corp.: 1964., 1635; Size: 155.5 x 120 cm.; Colored.; Bruce C. Heezen and Marie Tharp.
      Descriptive sheet accompanies physiographic diagram. It has five figures, of which three are maps: 3. Control chart. All sounding lines used in the preparation; 4. Physiographic provinces; and 5. Bathymetric sketch of the Indian Ocean. Size of these three maps: ca. 51 x 39 cm.